# Okwiri Oduor

okwiri.codes@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/okwiri-oduor-ab2010219/ github.com/cauliflowersingerbee +49 176 212 301 76

Web developer experienced in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, React Native, Angular, SQL, Node Js, and Git. Skilled in UX Design processes such as UX research, wireframing, prototyping, and usability testing. Extensive experience in writing and editing. Inquisitive, curious, constantly learning and growing.

#### **Work Experience**

#### Web Development • June 2021-February 2022

- Took part in intensive project-based online fullstack web development training program offered by Career Foundry, with a focus on Javascript, React, React Native and Angular
- Built portfolio website using React to showcase my work. The portfolio projects include complex fullstack applications such as an API built using both SQL and NoSQL methods, and client-side applications using React, Redux, React Native and Angular. Please see portfolio website here: https://cauliflowersingerbee.github.io/my-portfolio/

### UX Design • September 2021-March 2022

- Took part in immersive project-based online UX Design training program offered by Google and Coursera, with a focus on UX research, wireframing, prototyping, and usability testing
- Created three UX Design case studies based on UX research findings and application design processes

#### Freelance Writer & Editor • 2007-Present

- Wrote numerous published short stories, essays and a novel (release date April 2022)
- Editor at Iwalewabooks. Edited We Are F\*\*\*cking Here!, a book by a South African queer collective (Hola Africa), on safer sex, sexuality and gender • 2019-2020
- Artist Assistant for Iwalewahaus, in charge of curating a pop-up exhibition. Duties consisted of research, writing of wall texts, creation of art labels, and management of South African visual artist Mbongeni Buthelezi. • 2019-2020
- Co-writer and Story Consultant for Seven Thirty Films (Kenya & UAE). Analysis and troubleshooting of story concept. Reworked narrative and wrote new drafts of a film script • 2020
- Writer, Story Consultant, and Editor for Riyo Films (Kenya). Wrote and edited technical proposals and reports. Conceptualized and wrote scripts for various projects, including for a series of educational films for UNICEF. • 2017-2018

#### **Technical Skills**

#### Web Development

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- React
- Angular
- SQL databases
- NoSQL databases
- Git versioning
- Bootstrap
- Node Js

#### **UX** Design

- UX Research
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- Usability Testing
- Competitive analysis
- User Stories
- User Flows

#### **Software**

- VS Code
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe XD
- Figma
- Adobe InDesign
- PostgresSQL
- Balsamiq

## **Education**

The University of Iowa, 2017 Master of Fine Arts, Creative Writing

#### Certification

- Career Foundry, 2022 **Fullstack Web Development Certificate**
- Google Coursera, 2022 **UX Design Certificate**